# Darren Goring CV

5 Fauld lane, Fauld, Burton-on-Trent, Staffordshire DE13 9GU | M: 07968760379 | darren.goring@live.com

## **Summary**

Self-motivated pipe fitter, welder with over 18 years of experience in the power generation, food, beverage and pharmaceutical sectors. Recognised for assessing operational needs and developing solutions to save costs, improve revenues, and drive customer satisfaction. Resourceful and well-organised with excellent leadership and team building record.

## **Skills**

- Self-motivated
- Problem solving
- Time management
- Scheduling
- Attention to detail
- Team management
- Communication skills
- Budgeting
- Microsoft Office
- Team player
- Adaptable
- Willing to learn
- Flexible

# **Experience**

## PJ Douglas engineering ltd

#### Site Labourer - From 05/2000 to 08/2003

Working within the power generation sector on various power stations around the country, taking part in various maintenance and complete overhaul tasks. Gained vast experience in mechanical fitting, rigging, welding and fabrication tasks.

I became a useful part of the team in an environment where teamwork is key.

## **Able Engineering Itd**

#### Apprentice sheet metal worker, welder - From 08/2003 to 06/2007

After gaining an interest in welding and fabrication I decided to go back to college to gain some qualifications in the area.

Joined Able engineering as a mature apprentice and attended Burton on Trent college to obtain an Advanced diploma and NVQ 3 in fabrication and welding.

I carried out many fabrication and welding activities including stainless steel vessels from inception through to delivery and the installation of various types of pipework.

I gained various ASME IX 6G welding coding's within this employment which I still hold to this day.

I was deemed competent enough to work on various sites, these were in the food, beverage and pharmaceutical sectors and was asked to lead jobs on occasions.

## **Musk Engineering Itd**

Pipe fitter/welder/Site welder – From 08/2007 to 07/2019

Worked mainly on various sites around the UK within the food, beverage and pharmaceutical sectors, including general maintenance tasks to full new project installations,

I installed many types of pipe work systems from stainless steel thin wall and schedule pipework, copper and stainless Maypress pipe work and carbon steel welded and screwed pipework,

Within 3 years I had progressed to site Leading hand/foreman where I was trained and entrusted with site supervision (SSSTS trained).

An opportunity arose within the company to be become a site manager which I took, this involved 6 months of office-based training including quoting, this experience gave me an understanding of computer applications including Microsoft word and excel, gained <u>SMSTS</u> training in January 2018.

I then took this experience and training onto site where I worked directly with various clients from Cadburys and Nestle to Molson Coors, completing various pipework and plant installation projects including time critical shutdown projects.

I also quoted new work up to £50k without the requirement for sign off from my line manager.

I was managing teams of up to 15 employees ensuring all aspects of health and safety and budgetary requirements were met and all materials and equipment were readily available to complete the work.

## Self employed at DPG Site services ltd

Pipe fitter, welder, site manager – From 07/2019 to Current

Started my own limited company working as a self-employed Pipe fitter, welder with a Site management option.

## **Education**

Advanced modern apprenticeship completed in 2007 at Burton on Trent technical college.

NVQ 3 and Advanced diploma in fabrication and welding.

NVQ2 in key skills.

# **Additional training**

- Gold supervisors CSCS training card (valid till August 2024)
- IPAF 3a and 3b (valid till February 2021)
- PASMA tower user only (valid until March 2022)
- St Johns ambulance First aid at work training.

## Past training,

- CITB SSSTS training,
- · Confined space working,
- Asbestos awareness training,
- Abrasive wheels training,
- Forklift truck training,
- Personal harness training,
- Banksman training,
- Manual handling training,